[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Jeff Tu: Good afternoon,
&gt;&gt; Jeff Tu: 大家下午好
I'd like to welcome to you part
欢迎你们
two to Advances in Networking, a
进入网络结构进阶的第二个部分
continuation of the session from
这个部分是对上个
the past hour.
会议的一个延续
My name is Jeff Tu, and I'll be
我叫 Jeff Tu 接下来我会
taking you through the first
向你们介绍
topic.
第一个话题
In this session we'll discuss
在这个部分中 我们将会讨论
new URLSession developer API and
新的 URLSession 开发者 API 和
enhancements, networking best
一些改进 网络架构的最佳实践
practices, and other important
以及一些其他的
technology areas in networking.
网络架构中的重要技术
Our first topic is new
我们的第一个话题是新的
URLSession API.
URLSession API
But before that, I'd like to
但开始之前 我想先
review the underlying API we'll
回顾一下我们将要讨论的
be talking about, which is
基本 API
URLSession.
那就是 URLSession
URLSession is an easy-to-use API
URLSession 是在 iOS 7 和
for networking introduced in iOS
OS X Mavericks 中提出的一个很好用的
7 and OS X Mavericks.
网络设计 API
URLSession supports networking
URLSession 支持的网络协议
protocols like HTTP/2; HTTP/1.1;
包括 HTTP/2 HTTP/1.1
FTP; and custom streams with an
FTP 和一些自定义流
overall emphasis on URL loading.
它的重点在于 URL 加载
If you provide it an HTTPS URL,
如果你给它一个 HTTPS URL
it also automatically provides
它会自动提供你和网络服务器
the encryption and decryption of
之间的数据的
data between you and the web
加密和解密
Last year we deprecated
去年我们停用了
NSURLConnection API.
NSURLConnection API
So we encourage any new app
所以我们鼓励任何
development to occur with
新的使用 URLSession 的
URLSession.
app 开发
For more information on
如果想了解关于
URLSession, I encourage you to
URLSession 更多的信息 我建议你
review past WWDC sessions and
回看过去的 WWDC 会议
other online documentation.
和其他网上的资源
Recall that there are different
回忆一下 你可以创建
kinds of URLSession objects that
几种不同的 URLSession 对象
you can create.
你可以创建的
The basic object you can create
最基本的对象
is a default configuration
是一个默认配置的
URLSession object.
URLSession 对象
Default sessions have a behavior
默认对象的一个行为特点是
where a task either fetches a
它要么立刻可以
URL immediately; or if the
获取一个 URL 要么如果设备
device can't connect to the web
不能连接到网络服务器的话
server, fails immediately.
会立刻连接失败
URL loads can fail because the
URL 加载可能会失败
device isn't connected to the
因为设备无法连接到网络
Internet or if the server you're
或者你正在尝试连接的
trying to reach happens to be
服务器恰好
down.
不工作了
Those are just a couple of
这只是其中的
examples.
几个例子
Background URLSession objects,
另一方面 后台 URLSession 对象
on the other hand, don't have
则没有这种
this immediate fetch or fail
立刻获取或失效的情况
behavior but are scheduled out
它是根据进程而安排的
of process and continually
并且持续监控
monitored for network
与服务器之间的
connectivity to the server.
网络连接情况
There are more examples of a
有更多 URLSession 任务
URLSession task failing because
因为网络连接差
of bad connectivity.
而失败的例子
You might have no Internet
你可能会没有
connection, you might be in a
互联网连接
theatre with your device in
你可能正在一个剧院里
Airplane Mode or it should be in
你的手机开了飞行模式
Airplane Mode.
或者说它应该是飞行模式
Perhaps you have a session
可能你的连接对象
object where you've disallowed
不允许使用
cell usage but the user only has
数据网络 而用户只可以连接
cell connectivity.
数据网络
Or the server might only be
或者服务器
accessible behind a VPN and the
只有在 VPN 的情况下才可以访问
admin recently changed VPN
而管理员最近修改了
access.
VPN 权限
How do you as an app developer
你们作为 app 的开发者
deal with a network load that
将如何应对一个失败的
fails?
网络负载呢
In the past, we've advised you
过去 我们建议你
to use the SCNetworkReachability
使用 SCNetworkReachability
API to monitor when you might
API 来检测你何时
have connectivity again to the
能够再次获得
server.
服务器连接
Other approaches are polling
还有一些其他方法
every set period of time or
比如每个特定时段抽样
depending on the user to tap or
或者依赖于用户点击或拖动界面
drag to refresh the UI.
来进行刷新
The problem is that these
这些方法的问题在于
approaches add complexity to
它们把你的 app 变的
your apps and aren't always
更复杂 并且不总是
effective.
有效的
SCNetworkReachability only tells
SCNetworkReachability 只能
you that you might be able to
告诉你 你可能能
reach the server, not that you
连接到服务器
will.
而不是保证你能连接
You, our developers, have been
你作为开发者一直在
asking for an easier solution.
寻找一个更简单的解决方案
Wouldn't it be easier to say,
如果只需要说
then, "Please fetch me this
“请在网络可用时
resource when the network is
帮我获取这个资源”
available"?
不是更简单吗
We're happy to tell you about a
我们很高兴地告诉你们
new feature that lets you do
我们现在有了一个新功能
this.
允许你这样做
We call this the URLSession
我们称之为 URLSession
Adaptable Connectivity API.
Adaptable Connectivity API
This --
这个
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
This API is available now on all
这个 API 现在所有的平台
platforms.
都可用
By opting into this API, you
通过启用这个 API
tell URLSession that in the
你就可以告诉 URLSession
event that the task would fail
如果任务由于
because of a lack of
无法连接而失败
connectivity that it should wait
它应该是等待
for a connection to the server
与服务器连接
instead of failing.
而不是直接失败
How do you opt in?
那么怎么启用它呢
There's a new boolean property
有一个 boolean 属性
called waitsForConnectivity.
叫做 waitsForConnectivity
Set this to true, and then you
把它设成 True
get the new behavior.
然后你就可以获得这个新特性了
I'd like to repeat what this
我想重复一下这个
property does.
属性的功能
You go from the default behavior
你可以摆脱默认的那种
of load it now or fail now if I
要么加载要么如果无法连接
can't connect to load it now,
就失败的行为模式
but if I can't and would have
变成如果我无法连接
failed because of a lack of
并且因此而失败的情况下
connectivity, try again when I
当我有机会连接到服务器时
get a real chance to talk to the
重新尝试再次加载
The API also waits when it
如果遭遇了 DNS 故障时
encounters DNS failures as well
这个 API 也可以等
since one network's DNS service
因为一个网络的 DNS 服务
might fail to resolve but
可能无法解析 但是
another one may not.
另一个网络的可能可以
Please note that this boolean is
请注意你不需要
a no op for background sessions,
在后台会话中启用这个 API
as background URLSession objects
因为后台 URLSession 对象会
get this behavior automatically.
自动获取这种行为模式
We'll tell you later in this
我们会稍后
hour more about the differences.
向你们解释其中的区别
You may be wondering, "Can my
你可能会想
code get a notification if it's
“如果它进入等待状态时
in this waiting state?"
我的代码可以收到通知吗”
You might want to have the app
当它等待重新连接时
present other behavior while
你可能想要你的 app
it's waiting to connect.
展现其他功能
For example, having an offline
比如 做一个
browsing mode or a mode that
离线浏览模式
operates when the user is only
或者一个只有在用户使用数据网络时
on cell.
才用到的模式
If you would like to know when
如果你想知道
your app is in this waiting
何时你的 app 正处于这样的等待状态
state, you can optionally
你可以选择
implement the URLSession
运行 URLSession
taskIsWaitingForConnectivity
taskIsWaitingForConnectivity
delegate method.
委托功能
Note that this delegate method
请注意 这个委托功能
is only called if you've opted
只有在你已经把
into the waitsForConnectivity
waitsForConnectivity
property with a true value.
属性设为 True 时才可用
If you've done this, the
如果你已经这么做了的话
delegate method itself will be
这个委托功能只会
called only one time or not at
被运行一次
all if the task never had to
或者如果这个任务根本不需要等的话
wait.
它就不需要运行
We recommend that your apps
我们建议你的 app
always opt into the
一直将
waitsForConnectivity property.
waitsForConnectivity 属性设为打开状态
This is because even when you
这是因为即使
opt in, the task will still try
你打开了它 每个任务也会试图
to run immediately.
立刻运行
The task will only wait if it
任务只有在它
can't connect to the server.
不能连接到服务器时才会等待
There are rare exceptions to
不过也有一些
opting into the property,
少有的例外
For example, if you had a
比如 如果你有一个
URLSession task whose purpose
URLSession 任务 它的目的
was to buy stock at market
是以市场价格购入股票
price, you'd want that to run
你可能需要它
now or fail now and not wait
要么运行要么失败
until you had an Internet
而不是等到你再次获得
connection.
网络连接
I'd also like to mention that
值得一提的是
when you opt into
当你打开
waitsForConnectivity, the
waitsForConnectivity 后
timeout interval for request
请求超时响应时间的计时器
timer starts only after you've
只会在你
connected to the server.
连接到服务器后才会启动
Timeout interval for resource,
资源的超时响应功能
however, is always respected.
是被尊重的
Let's summarize how we would use
我们来总结一下我们可以
the API and then go through a
怎样使用这个 API 然后就开始
code example.
看一些示范代码
The main thing is to opt into
主要就是打开
the waitsForConnectivity
waitsForConnectivity
property.
属性
You would create and resume the
你可以跟以前一样
URLSessionTask as before.
创建或者继续使用 URLSessionTask
If the device can't connect to
如果设备无法连接到
the server, we'd call a delegate
服务器 我们就会启用一个
callback if you implemented it
委托回调功能 并且只会
and only once.
启用一次
All other URLSession methods are
其他的 URLSession 功能
still called same as before.
还是跟之前一样启用
Remember, though, that this API
不过要记住
only has an effect for
这个 API 只会对
non-background sessions.
非后台会话的任务起作用
Let's go through a sample code.
我们一起来看一个示范代码
First create a session
首先创建一个会话
configuration object and make
配置对象 并且
one for default session type.
把它设置成默认类型
Opt into the
选择启用
waitsForConnectivity property.
waitsForConnectivity 属性
Create the session object and
创建会话对象
set the URL you want to load.
并且设置好你想要加载的 URL
Use the session object to create
用会话对象来创建
a task object.
一个任务对象
And finally, resume the task to
最后重新开始
get it started.
这个任务
Even with adaptable
即使有可用的
connectivity, your request may
连接 你的请求也
still fail for other reasons.
仍然可能因为其他原因失败
For example, you could connect
比如 你可能已经
to the server, but a new data
连接到服务器 但是一个新来的
center employee might unplug a
数据中心的工作人员可能拔掉了
server, cause the network
服务器 导致网络
connection to drop, and all your
连接断开
apps on your phone might
然后你的手机上所有的 app
disappear.
都会消失
Or your device connects to the
或者你的设备连接到服务器
server and sends an HTTP
并且发送了一个 HTTP 请求
request, but there's so much
但是数据流量太大
traffic that the request times
导致请求超时
For situations like these, we'd
针对这种情况
like you to consult online
我们建议你查询
resources that go into more
网上资源 它们会提供
detail on what you can do.
更多关于你应该怎么做的细节
Retrying network loads in a
不过 在紧密循环中
tight loop, though, is almost
重试网络加载
always a bad idea.
往往都不是一个好主意
You asked for a better way to
你希望得到一个更好的
load network resources.
加载网络资源的方法
Better than polling for network
比等待网络
connectivity to the server and
连接到服务器更好
better than reachability API
也比使用一个
that won't guarantee a
不能保证一定能
connection to the server.
连接到服务器的 API 更好
Let URLSession do the work for
让 URLSession
you.
来帮你
Opt into the
启用
waitsForConnectivity Adaptable
waitsForConnectivity 适应性
Connectivity API.
连接 API
If you opt in, the request will
如果你启用了 这个请求
still run immediately with no
仍然会立刻运行
performance penalty and only
不会有任何性能损失
wait if you can't connect to the
并且只有在你无法连接到
server.
服务器的情况下等待
Once it can connect, your
一旦它可用连接
URLSession task behaves just
你的 URLSession 任务就会像
like it did before.
之前一样工作
Continuing our theme of what's
继续我们关于新进展的主题
new, I'd like to pass the mic to
我要把麦克风传给
my colleague, Jeff Jenkins.
我的同事 Jeff Jenkins
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Jeff Jenkins: Thanks, Jeff.
&gt;&gt; Jeff Jenkins: 谢谢 Jeff
Well, good afternoon.
大家下午好
Hope you guys are having a great
希望你们喜欢这场 WWDC
And I'm exciting to be here and
我很高兴来到这里
thrilled to talk to you a little
很高兴向你们介绍
bit more about some enhancements
我们对 URLSessionTask API
we've made to the URLSessionTask
所做的一些改进
Now, first I want to spend a
首先 我想花一点时间
little bit of time talking about
跟你们谈谈
background URLSession.
后台 URLSession
We haven't talked a whole lot
我们没有好好介绍过它
about it, so let me give you a
所以请让我来告诉你们
little bit of background on
关于它的一些
that.
背景知识
The background session
后台会话的
URLSession API allows your
URLSession API 允许你的 app
application to perform
在即使不运行
networking even if your process,
或你在处理的过程中
your application isn't running.
也可以进行联网
We monitor the system
我们会监控
conditions, CPU, battery, all
系统状态 CPU 电池等等
sorts of things to really find
各种事情来帮你找到
of right time to do your
完成联网任务的
networking tasks.
正确时间
Now, of course, if you implement
现在 当然 如果你
various delegate methods, we're
执行一些委托功能
going to wake up your app and
我们可以唤醒你的 app
call those delegate callbacks so
然后执行委托回调
that you can handle that
这样你就可以
information.
处理这些信息
And, of course, we're going to
当然 我们会确保
make sure your app is running
当你的任务完成时
when your task completes so that
你的 app 仍然在运行
you can then process that data.
这样你就能够处理那些数据
Now, one of the great use cases
现在 后台 URLSession 的一个
for background URLSession is
好用之处就是
taking advantage of another
利用了系统中的
feature on the system, which is
另一个功能
background app refresh.
就是后台 app 刷新
Now, what this really does is
现在 它的做法是
allows your application to have
允许你的 app 掌握
the most current, the freshest
最近 最新的数据
data, right?
对不对
There's nothing more frustrating
没有什么比
than pulling your device out,
你拿出设备
launching an app, and the first
打开一个app
thing you're greeted with is
而你看到的第一个东西
some sort of spinner, right?
就是一个在转的圈圈更让人心烦了
You're waiting for this
你在等着
application to start pulling
这个 app 启动
down data.
获取数据
You want that data right away.
你希望马上得到那个数据
You want to be able to get that
你希望马上把那个
data to your user so your user
数据传送给你的用户
is excited and happy to use your
这样你的用户就会
app.
很开心地使用你的 app
Background app refresh is a way
后台 app 刷新就能让你
to do this.
做到这样
It's a way to tell the system
它可以告诉系统
that, "Hey, in the future I want
“嘿 未来我希望
to be able to be launched so
可以被启动
that I can refresh my data so I
这样我就可以刷新我的数据
have the most important
让我获取最重要的
information," maybe stock
信息”可能是
information, or weather
股票信息 或者是
forecast, other important things
天气预报 或者是
that your app does.
你的 app 提供的其他信息
Now, this applies to
现在它可以
applications, as well as watchOS
应用于 app
complications.
包括 watchOS 版本
And if you want to learn a
如果你想
little bit more in depth about
更加深入了解
background app refresh, you can
后台 app 刷新 你可以
go back to 2013 WWDC, as well as
回顾 2013 年的 WWDC
last year's 2016 WWDC and look
以及去年的 WWDC
at these sessions for more
查看相关会议
So let's look at background app
那么让我们来看一看
refresh in action; what is it
后台 app 刷新的运行 它到底
really doing?
在做什么
And to do that, we kind of need
为此 我们可能需要
to look at the state of your
看一看你的 app 的状态
We're interested in three states
三种状态
here: A running state, suspended
运行状态 暂停状态
state, or a background state.
或是后台状态
Now, with your app running,
现在 你的 app 正在运行中
you're going to opt into
你要启用
background app refresh.
后台 app 刷新
You're going to say, "In the
你就要告诉系统
future, run my app, make sure my
“未来 需要运行我的 app
app runs so that I can get the
确保它在运行 使我可以
latest information."
获得最新的信息”
And then your process could be
然后你的进程将被暂停
And in the future your process
未来你的进程
is now running, your app is now
在运行时 你 app 就可以
going to be able to ask for new
要求获取新的数据
data.
跟优秀的开发者一样
app is using URLSession API.
这个 app 在使用 URLSession API
In fact, it uses a background
事实上 它使用的是一个后台
URLSession.
URLSession
It creates a URLSession task and
它创建一个 URLSession 任务
schedules this task to run and
让这个任务运行
grab the data that your
并且抓取你的 app
application needs.
所需要的数据
Now, your process could go away
你的进程在这个时候
at this point, but then at some
可能会停止 但是在某个时候
point URLSession is going to run
URLSession 会运行你的任务
your task and it's going to run
如果一切顺利的话
it to completion hopefully if
你的 app 也就会运行
everything goes well.
直到任务完成
And you're going to get the
这样你就会获得数据了
data.
我们将会在后台
launch your application and
运行你的 app
allow you to process that
允许你来处理
completed task and process that
那个完成了的任务
data that we've fetched for you.
以及我们为你抓取的数据
And then at some point the user
某个时候 用户会
is going to launch your app,
打开你的 app
it's going to come foreground,
它就会到前台来
and boom, they've got the
然后他们就会获得
freshest data there.
最新的数据
So this is great.
这可棒极了
But we looked at this flow and
当我们观察了这个流程
said, "Hmm, maybe there's
我们说“嗯 也许
something we can do to help our
我们可以做点什么
developers improve their
帮助我们的开发者来
applications on our platforms."
在我们的平台上改进他们的 app"
And we think we can do something
我们认为我们可以
for you.
为你们做点什么
The first problem that we want
我们想要解决的第一个问题
to solve is we noticed there's
就是我们注意到
an extra background launch that
必须有一个另外的后台运行
had to happen just for you to
你才能创建
create the URLSession task.
这个 URLSession 任务
And as we all know, anytime your
我们都知道
process is launched, what does
任何时候你开始这个进程
that do?
意味着什么
It impacts battery life,
意味着它会影响电池寿命
requires CPU burden.
对 CPU 造成负担
So that's not necessarily great
我们这些无关紧要的工作
for the device if we're doing
恐怕对设备并不是件好事
extraneous work, and we really
而且其实我们真的
don't need to be doing that.
不需要这么做
The other problem we'd like to
我们想要解决的
solve are stale network
另一个问题是陈旧的
requests, right?
网络请求 对吧？
You're asking URLSession to do
你可以让 URLSession
work.
来帮你解决
And at some point in the future,
但是在未来的某个时刻
that work is going to complete.
这个任务会被完成
Well, what happens between when
那么在你要求任务开始
you ask for the work to be done
和任务完成之间
and when it actually got done?
要发生点什么呢？
Maybe there was some change in
也许其中情况发生了一些变化
context and that original
使得最初的
request doesn't make sense
请求没有意义了
So we need to give you an
所以我们需要给予你们
opportunity to really, if
这样的机会
there's a context change, let us
如果情况发生改变
know about that and get rid of
让我们知道 并且最终
these stale network requests.
去掉这些陈旧的网络请求
Because there's nothing worse
因为没有什么会比
than getting data and going, "I
获得数据后发现
can't do anything with it," and
“我用它什么也做不了”然后
throw it away.
把它丢掉更糟的了
And the last problem we think we
最后一个我们认为
could help you with is helping
可以帮到你们的是
us know how to best schedule
让我们知道如何更好的
your URLSession tasks.
安排你的 URLSession 任务
When is the most optimal, best
什么时候是
time in the system to be able to
在系统中运行
run your task so that we can get
你的任务的最优时间
your data in the most efficient
这样我们就可以
way for you to display that so
用最有效的方式帮你获得需要展示的数据
that your users are excited and
让你的用户
delighted by that data?
对数据感到满意
Let's look at what we did.
让我们来看看我们做了什么
We're introducing the
我们提出了
URLSessionTask scheduling API.
URLSessionTask 调度 API
Now, this is available across
它在我们所有的平台上
all of our platforms.
都可以使用
It's available in the beta
它在你们在 WWDC
builds that you have received
收到的测试版上
here at WWDC.
也可以用
And we encourage you to take a
我们希望你们可以
deep look at this.
深入了解一下
Now, what we've done first is we
首先我们提供了
provided a new property.
一个新的属性
This is a property on
它是
URLSessionTask object.
URLSessionTask 对象的属性
It is called earliestBeginDate.
叫做 earliestBeginDate
And what you're going to do here
你要做的是
is provide a date to us in the
为我们提供一个时间
future when you want your task
你想什么时候
to be eligible for running.
允许你的任务准备好开始运行
I use that word eligible because
我用了“准备好”这个词
it's important.
因为它很重要
It doesn't mean that this is the
这不是意味着
point in time when your task
这是你的任务开始运行
will run, it will do networking;
开始联网的时间点
it's just telling the system, "I
它只是告诉系统
would like my task to be
“我希望我的任务
eligible so that it can run."
准备好了 以至于它能够运行了”
And we're still bound by system
同时我们还是需要遵守
policies as to when we can make
系统规定 何时
the networking happen for this
我们可以让这个任务
task.
开始联网
It's only applicable to
它只可以用于
background URLSessions and tasks
后台的 URLSession
built off of background
和建立在后台
URLSession.
URLSession 上的任务
Let's take a look at how this
让我们来看看
property in conjunction with
这个属性和其他的
other existing properties really
现有的属性一起是如何
allows you to do some fine-grain
允许你进行一些精细的安排的
So you'll create a
你需要创建一个
URLSessionTask and, of course,
URLSessionTask 当然
you'll call resume on it so that
你需要启用重调
we know that this task can now
这样我们就知道
be put into the queue so that
我们可以把这个任务放入队列
work can happen.
然后开始工作
You'll -- and at this point the
在这个时候
task will be in a waiting state.
这个任务应该处于等待状态
We're waiting for the
我们在等着
earliestBeginDate to happen.
earliestBeginDate 生效
And as soon as that is hit, that
当到了那个时间点后
task becomes eligible for
这个任务就准备好运行了
Now, you can use the existing
你就可以使用现有的
timeoutIntervalForResource to
timeoutIntervalForResource
really control how long your app
来控制你的 app
is willing to wait for at that
要等多久来
resource to get loaded, right?
加载那个资源 对不对
You might set some amount of
你可以设置一定的时间
time to say, "After this point
告诉系统说“在这个时间点之后
in time, this resource isn't
这个资源对我而言
interesting to me anymore."
就没有用了”
And that interval of time covers
这个时间间隔
from resume to when that timeout
涵盖了从重调度到
happens based on the value you
依据你在 timeoutIntervalForResource 中
place in
输入的值而得到的超时时间
timeoutIntervalForResource.
之间的间隔
Now, I want to go back to the
现在 我想要回到
original background app refresh
我们之前看到的
workflow that we looked at
后台 app 刷新的
earlier.
工作流
Right? We noticed there was a
我们可以看到
couple of background launches
其中有一些启动了
that occurred.
后台程序
But with this new API we're able
不过使用这个新的 API
to get rid of one of those.
我们可以剔除掉它们其中的一个
So the way that your app will
你的 app 工作的方式就变成了
work is while your running,
当你的 app 在运行时
you're going to create a
你要创建一个
URLSessionTask; you'll opt into
URLSessionTask 你需要
our new scheduling API by
启用我们的新的调度 API
setting an earliestBeginDate;
设置一个 earliestBeginDate
then your process can go to
然后你的进程会
sleep.
进入睡眠
We're going to complete the work
我们会帮你完成
for you.
余下的工作
And when that work is available,
当我们完成这部分工作之后
we're going to background launch
我们将会在后台
you that one time and allow you
启用你的 app 一次然后
to process the resulting data.
允许你开始处理收到的数据
And then when the user brings
当你的用户把你的 app
your app to the foreground,
带来前台后
boom, it's got the freshest,
他们会得到
most current data.
最新的数据
And we've been able to solve
这样我们就可以解决
that one problem of that
这个多余的
additional background app
后台 app 启动问题
launch.
让 app 在系统中运行更顺畅
the system, and we think that's
我们认为这是
great.
很好的改进
So that's problem number one
这就是我们解决的
solved.
第一个问题
Let's look at problem number
我们来看一看第二个问题
two, the stale network fetches.
过时的网络抓取
We want to give you an
我们希望给你们
opportunity to alter future
一个更改未来请求的机会
So you might have given us a
你可能给过我们一个请求了
request, but the context might
但是情况可能
change.
发生了变化
We've introduced a new delegate
我们提出了一个新的
callback on a
基于
URLSessionTaskDelegate titled
URLSessionTaskDelegate 的委托回调功能叫做
willBeginDelayedRequest.
willBeginDelayedRequest.
With this delegate, you'll be
使用它 你就可以
able to be called at the moment
在你的任务
when your task is about to start
要开始联网时
networking.
被调用
So it is you've told this that
如果你告诉系统
the task is eligible and the
这个任务准备好了
system now has decided yes, this
那么系统就会认为
is the right time to do the
好的 这就是联网的
networking.
最好时机
We're going to call this
我们就会启用
delegate method, if you
这个委托功能
implement it, and allow you to
如果你安装了的话
make some decisions about this
它会允许你对这个任务
task.
作出决定
Now, this will only be called
只有你安装了这个功能
one, if you implement it; also,
并且
if you opt into the scheduling
如果你
API by setting an
通过设置一个 earliestBeginDate 来
earliestBeginDate.
启用了调度 API 的话它才会启用
And, again, this is only
并且 这也只对
available on background
后台的 URLSessions 可用
And as I mentioned, this is an
并且正如我所提过的那样
optional delegate.
它是可选的
And I want to take a second here
我想在这里停一下
to have you really think about
希望你们可以认真思考一下
this because it's important,
因为这真的很重要
this delegate method.
这个委托功能
As with all delegate methods,
和其他所有的委托功能
they're all opt into.
都是你可以选择采用的
But this one will cause some
但是这一个会导致一些
interesting side effect that
其他有趣的事情发生
I'll show you in a minute.
我等一下会向你们展示
You really need to think about,
你真的需要想一想
"Can my application determine
“我的 app 能够确定
context, the viability of a
一个请求在未来的
request in the future?"
可行性吗”
Now, there's a completion
现在 一个 Completion Handler
handler that's passed to this
被加入到这个
delegate method.
委托功能
And you need to give a
而你则需要
disposition to URLSession.
给 URLSession 一个信号
You need to tell us does the
你需要告诉我们
original request, does it still
原始的请求是否
make sense?
还有继续处理
Go ahead and proceed.
的意义
Or maybe the context has changed
或者也许情况已经发生改变
enough and you need to make some
你需要做一些调整
modifications, maybe a different
也许是一个
URL or maybe a header value's
不同的 URL 也许一个标题值
different and you want to go
不同了 而你想要
ahead and modify that request at
在这个时候 在联入网络之前
this point in time right before
及时更改
the networking happens.
这个请求
Or you might make the decision
或者你会决定
this request is just useless at
这个请求在此时已经没有用了
this point, cancel.
取消它
We don't want to do stale
我们不想处理
requests.
过时的请求
So now if we go back to this
现在 如果我们回到这个
workflow and we go back to my
工作流 回到我之前
comment about really thinking
所说的认真思考
about this delegate method, you
这个功能
will see that we're kind of back
你就会发现我们似乎
to that original workflow where
回到了那个有
there's two background launches
两次后台启动
in order to satisfy this URL
来满足这个 URL 任务的工作流了
Right? But we have to stop and
对不对 但是我们需要
think about that.
停下来思考
What is more expensive,
哪一种的代价更高
performing a stale network load
是执行一次过时的网络加载
or a mere application background
还是一个 app 的
launch?
后台启动
It is way more expensive to the
对于系统来说
system to do stale loads, get
完成过时加载
all this data, and then decide I
获取全部的数据 然后决定
don't need it and pitch it.
我不需要它然后扔掉它 代价要高多了
Okay? So we want you to really
OK  所以我们希望你们
think about this new delegate
能够认真思考这个
method and whether your
委托功能 以及
application has the ability to
你们的 app 是不是有这个能力
really understand the viability
真正了解你的请求
of your requests in the future.
在未来的可行性
Hopefully that make sense to
希望你们明白
Now, the third problem we want
现在 我们要解决的
to solve is how do we schedule
第三个问题是我们如何
your request in a most optimal,
在系统中以
most intelligent way in our
最优化 最智能的方式
system?
调度你的请求
There's some information that in
在 URLSession 中有一些信息
URLSession we just don't know
是我们所不知道的
So we're providing a little bit
那么我们对我们的 API
of change to our API to allow
稍稍做了一些改变
you to explain to us some
可以让你向我们
information about your requests
解释你的请求
and also about your responses.
和你的回应的信息
We're giving you two properties,
我们给出两种属性
the first one is countOfBytes
第一个是 countOfBytes
ClientExpectsToSend, and the
ClientExpectsToSend
second one is countOfBytes
第二个是 countOfBytes
ClientExpectsToReceive.
ClientExpectsToReceive.
We think you know more about
我们相信你对你的请求
your requests.
更了解
Maybe you have a stream body
也许你想在一个请求上
that you want to attach to a
附加一个主体流
request, we don't know about
而我们并不知道
that.
而你可能知道
We don't know about your servers
我们不了解你的服务器
and the size of data your
也不知道你的服务器传送回的
servers' shipping back.
数据的大小
We believe you have some insight
我们相信你对此更了解
to that.
而这些会给我们一些提示
how we can in a most optimal,
告诉我们如何以
intelligent way schedule your
最优化和最智能的方式
tasks.
来调度你的任务
If you don't know, well, then
如果你不知道 那么
you can always specify
你可以写
NSURLSessionTransferSizeUnknown.
NSURLSessionTransferSizeUnknown
So that solves the third
这就解决了第三个问题
problem.
我们来看一看
new API works in code.
这个新的 API 用代码怎么写
It's very easy to use.
它用起来很简单
First thing we're going to do is
我们要做的第一件事情就是
create a URLSession background
创建一个 URLSession
configuration.
后台配置
We're then going to create a
然后我们要创建一个
session based on that
基于这个配置的会话
Once we have that, we're going
一旦我们有了它
to now generate a URLRequest,
我们就可以生成一个 URLRequest,
specify the URL we want to go
指定我们想去的 URL
to, maybe set a header value,
也可以设置一个标题值
something that makes sense for
设一个对你的任务
your task.
有意义的标题
Again, this is just an example.
再说一遍 这只是一个例子
And now we're going to create a
现在我们要创建一个
task that encapsulates that
任务 在该会话中
request on that session.
封装那个请求
And we're going to opt into the
然后我们要选择采用
new scheduling API by setting
这个新的调度 API
the earliestBeginDate property
通过设置 earliestBeginDate 属性
and give us a date.
并给我们一个时间
In this example we say two hours
在这个例子中 我们举个例子
from now I want this task to be
从现在开始两小时后我希望这个任务
eligible to be run.
已经准备好运行了
And I'm also going to give some
我也会给
hints to URLSession and say,
URLSession 一些暗示 告诉它
"This is a small request,
“这是一个小请求
there's no body, I've just set
没有主体 我只设置了
one header, maybe 80 bytes."
一个标题 大概 80 个字节
And then my server probably is
我的服务器大概会
going to send about a 2K
传送 2KB 的数据
response to this.
作为响应”
And with all URLSession tasks,
对于所有的 URLSession  任务
make sure you call resume.
请确保你可以重调度
Now, how does the new delegate
那么 新的委托功能
work?
怎么工作的呢
Well, we decided I know context.
我决定我了解情况
I can make some intelligent
我在未来可以为
decisions about my networking
我的联网任务作出
tasks in the future.
充满智慧的决定
So I've implemented
所以我使用了
willBeginDelayedRequest.
willBeginDelayedRequest
So in our example here what I've
在我们的案例中
decided to do is to modify the
我决定修改请求
I'm going to take the original
我要删除原始请求
request, create a new
然后创建一个新的
updatedRequest.
updatedRequest
I'm going to maybe change a
我将修改标题
value in the header that makes
中的一个值
more sense now that this task is
让它对任务更有意义
actually going to do some
现在这个任务事实上
networking.
要开始联入网络了
Time has passed, I have new
时间过去了 我有了一些
information.
新的信息
I put that information on that
我把这些信息加入到
task.
这个任务里
And then I'm going to call the
然后我要启用
completionHandler and use a
completionHandler 并且使用一个
disposition of useNewRequest and
useNewRequest 的配置
passed it that new request.
把它作为一个新的请求
If you take a look at our header
如果你看一看我们的
file, you can see other
标题文件 你会看到
dispositions available to you in
这个 completionHandler 功能中的
this completionHandler call.
其他可用的配置
So let me recap the scheduling
那么让我来总结一下我们
API that we're introducing here.
介绍的这个调度 API
Background URLSession is an
后台 URLSession 是一个
awesome API for doing networking
在网络连接方面的很好用的 API
that allows your application to
它允许你的 app
not even be running and have
甚至不用运行就可以
this networking happen for you.
获得这个网络连接
Our new scheduling API will
我们的新的调度 API
allow you to delay your requests
允许你延迟请求
so that they can, you know,
这样它们就可以
obtain and pull down the
为你的 app
freshest information for your
获取最新的信息
And it's really we give you an
我们给你们机会
opportunity to alter those
来依据
things based on the context and
实际情况和
the time at when the networking
网络连接实际发生的时间
is actually going to happen.
进行一些调整
The other part of this API
这个 API 的另一部分改进
change is to allow you to give
是允许你来给我们
hints to us so that we can be
一些提示 让我们可以
super intelligent and make these
变的更加智能
tasks run at the most optimal
让这些任务在设备上
time on these devices.
在最佳时机运行
Now, I'd like to turn the time
现在 我要将时间让给
over to Stuart Cheshire, an
Stuart Cheshire
Apple distinguished engineer.
一个苹果的杰出的工程师
And thank you for your time.
谢谢你们的聆听
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Stuart Cheshire: Thank you,
&gt;&gt; Stuart Cheshire: 谢谢 Jeff
Jeff.
现在我们要谈一谈
enhancements in URLSession.
URLSession 中的改进
We have four things to cover,
我们一共要涵盖四件事情
let's move through them.
让我们一一来讨论
Often you want to show a
你们往往想要展示一个
progress bar to indicate to the
进度条来告诉
users how progress is being
你的用户现在的
made.
进度如何
And right now this is a little
现在这个工作有一点
bit cumbersome.
繁琐
There are four variables that
你需要
you need to monitor with
用 Key-value Observing 检测
Key-value Observing.
四个变量
And sometimes the
并且有时候
countOfBytesExpectedToReceive or
countOfBytesExpectedToReceive 或者
Send is not always available.
Send 不总是可用的
The good news now in iOS 11 is
现在一个好消息是在 iOS 11 中
URLSessionTask has adopted the
URLSessionTask 已经采用了
ProgressReporting protocol.
ProgressReporting 协议
You can get a progress object
你可以从
from the URLSessionTask, and
URLSessionTask 获得一个进度对象
that gives you a variable
它会给你一个变量
fractionCompleted, which is a
叫做 fractionCompleted
number in the range zero to one.
其实是一个从零到一之间的数字
You can also provide strings to
你还可以加字符串
give more detail about what the
以提供关于操作的更多信息
You can attach that progress
你可以把那个进度对象
object to a UIProgressView or an
添加到 UIProgressView 或者
NSProgressIndicator to get an
NSProgressIndicator 以获得
automatic progress bar.
一个自动进度条
You can also combine multiple
你也可以把多个
progress objects into a parent
进度对象结合成一个
progress object when you're
母进度对象
performing multiple tasks, such
当你在进行多任务操作时
as downloading a file,
比如下载文件
decompressing a file, and then
解压缩文件
handling the data.
然后处理数据
So that makes your progress
这会让你报告进度
reporting much simpler.
这一过程更简单一些
The binding between a
URLSessionTask 和
URLSessionTask and the progress
进度对象之间的绑定
object is bidirectional.
是双向的
So if you suspend a
所以如果你暂停了一个
URLSessionTask, that is the same
URLSessionTask 就等于
as pausing the progress object.
暂停了进度对象
If you pause the progress
如果你暂停了进度对象
object, that is the same as
那也就等于
suspending the URLSessionTask.
暂停了 URLSessionTask.
We now have support for the
我们现在有针对
Brotli compression algorithm.
Brotli 压缩算法的支持
In tests this compresses about
在测试中 它比 gzip 的压缩速度
15% better than gzip, which
快大约 15% 左右
results in faster network
这带来了更快的网络访问
Like other new compression
和其他新的压缩方案一样
schemes, this is only used over
它只在
encrypted connections to avoid
加密连接中使用
confusing middle boxes that
以避免使
might not recognize this
可能无法辨别此压缩的
compression.
中间框产生混淆
Because Safari uses URLSession,
由于 Safari 使用 URLSession
that's also means Safari gets
这也意味着 Safari
the benefit of this new Brotli
也可以享受这个新的 Brotli
compression algorithm.
压缩算法带来的好处
And many major websites have
很多主要网站也
already announced support for
已经宣布了在他们的网页服务中
Brotli in their web service.
支持 Brotli 算法
Our next topic is the Public
我们的下一个话题是 Public
Suffix List.
Suffix List
The Public Suffix List is
Public Suffix List 有时候
sometimes called the effective
也被称为有效
top-level domain list.
一级域名列表
And this is important for
这对于确定
determining where administrative
互联网命名空间中
boundaries occur in the
管理边界的位置
namespace of the Internet.
很重要
One thing we don't want to allow
我们不允许
is for a website to set a cookie
一个网站在 .com 域上
on the com domain, which is then
设置一个 cookie 然后
accessible to any other dot com
任何以 .com 结尾的公司都可以访问它
So you might be tempted to make
所以你可能会试图
a rule that you can't set
建立一个规则 要求不能
cookies on top level domains,
在一级域名上设置 cookie
only on second level and lower.
只能在第二级或更低级上设置
But domains are named
但是在世界上的不同地方
differently in different parts
域名的名字也是不一样的
In America, Apple.com and
在美国 Apple.com 和
FileMaker.com are different
FileMaker.com 是不同的两个公司
But in Australia many, many
但是在澳大利亚
companies are under com.au, and
很多很多公司都用 com.au
that doesn't make them all the
但那并不意味着它们是
same company.
同一个公司
So the Public Suffix List is a
所以 Public Suffix List 是一堆
file of rules and patterns that
规则和模式
tells software how to judge
它告知软件如何判断
where administrative boundaries
管理边界的位置
This is used for partitioning
它用于
cookies, and it's used by the
划分 cookies
URLSession APIs.
URLSession API 也使用它
And if you use the
如果你直接使用
HTTPCookieStorage APIs directly,
HTTPCookieStorage API
it's supported there, too.
它也同样支持
We used to update this in
我们曾经在
software updates, but now with
软件升级中更新了它
the more rapid progress in
但是现在随着创建
creating top level domains,
一级域名的进展越来越快
we've changed to doing this over
我们已经改为空中更新
We could push a new list every
如果我们愿意
two weeks if we wanted to.
我们可以每两周推出一个新的列表
URLSessionStreamTask is the API
如果你只是想要一个字节流
you would use if you just want a
你可以使用
byte stream.
URLSessionStreamTask API
If you're not doing HTTP Style
如果你不想做 HTTP Style
Gets but say you want to write a
Gets 但是比如说你想写一个
mail client,
邮件客户端
URLSessionStreamTask gives you a
URLSessionStreamTask 会给你一个
simple byte stream.
简单的字节流
It supports upgrading to TLS
它支持使用 STARTTLS 选项
with the STARTTLS option.
升级到 TLS
If you have existing code that
如果你现在的代码
is written using the old
是使用之前的
NSInputStream and NSOutputStream
NSInputStream 和 NSOutputStream API 写的
APIs, you can extract those
你可以从一个
objects from a
URLSessionStreamTask 中提取那些对象
URLSessionStreamTask to use your
以使用你之前的代码
But for any new code you're
但是对于你所写的
writing, we strongly recommend
任何新代码 我们都强烈推荐
that you use the new native
你使用新的本地
URLSessionStreamTask APIs.
URLSessionStreamTask API
We announced this a couple of
我们在 2015 年的 WWDC
years ago at WWDC 2015.
宣布了这件事
What we have new for you now is
现在我们为你们提供的新进展是
automatic navigation of
身份验证代理的
authenticating proxies.
自动导航
If the proxy requires
如果这个代理要求
credentials, then we will
取得帐密 那么我们就会
automatically extract those from
自动从钥匙串中提取
the key chain or promptly the
或者立刻代表你
user on your behalf.
从用户处获取
So we've covered the
那么我们现在已经
enhancements for URLSession,
讲完了 URLSession 的一些改进
let's move on.
我们下面继续
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
Thank you.
谢谢
Tips and hints that we've
下面是我们从数年来
learned from our years helping
帮助开发者的经验中得到的一些
developers.
建议
Number one rule: Don't use BSD
头号规则：
Sockets.
别用 BSD Sockets
And by the same token, we
同样的道理
encourage you not to embed
我们建议你不要嵌入
libraries that are based on BSD
基于 BSD Sockets 的库
Because we do lots of work, as
因为正如今天你所听到的这样
you've been hearing today, to
我们做了很多工作
provide benefits to your
来为你开发 app
applications.
提供方便
We provide Wi-Fi Assist so that
我们推出了 Wi-Fi Assist
your application succeeds
使你的 app 在 Wi-Fi 网络不好时
instead of failing when Wi-Fi
仍然可以运行
isn't working.
而不失败
We provide techniques to
我们提供了可以
minimize CPU use and minimize
最小化 CPU 和电池使用量的
battery use to give users longer
技术 给用户更长的
battery life.
电池寿命
We have the ability to do tasks
我们能在你的 app
in the background when your
不运行的时候
application isn't even running.
在后台处理任务
And the third-party libraries
而第三方库不在
just can't do anything when
内存中运行时
they're not in memory running.
它们本质上是什么也做不了的
And final bit of advice: Always
最后一点建议
try to use connect-by-name APIs
始终使用通过名称连接的 API
as opposed to APIs where you
而不要使用需要
resolve a name to an IP address
你把名称解析成一个 IP 地址
and then connect to the address.
然后连接到地址的 API
We talked earlier about the
我们之前讨论了
requirement for IPv6 support.
IPv6 支持的要求
And the reason that almost all
并且你们几乎所有的 app 都可以
of your apps worked perfectly is
完美运行的一个原因就是
because when you use
当你使用
connect-by-name APIs, you don't
通过名称连接的 API 时
get involved with the IP
你不需要接触 IP 地址
And if you're not involved with
如果你不需要接触
the IP address, you don't need
IP 地址 你就不用去
to care whether it's v4 or v6,
关心它是 v4 还是 v6
it just works.
它会自动工作
Another question we often get is
我们经常收到的一个问题是
about the timeout values.
关于超时值
So I want to recap that.
所以我要再说一下
The timeoutIntervalForResource
timeoutIntervalForResource
is the time limit for fetching
表示抓取整个资源的
the entire resource.
时间限制
By default, this is seven days.
默认的情况下 应该是 7 天
If the entire resource has not
如果在那之前
been fetched by that time, it
没有抓取到整个资源的话
will fail.
任务就会失败
timeoutIntervalForRequest is a
timeoutIntervalForRequest 是一个
timer that only starts once the
计时器 只有在传输开始后
transfer starts.
才会开始计时
Once it starts, if your transfer
一旦它开始计时
stalls and ceases making
如果你的传输卡顿或者
progress for that time-out
在那个超时值时没什么进展
value, that when that timer will
计时器将被触发
We have seen developers that
我们见过一些开发人员
take their old NSURLConnection
使用他们旧的
code and convert it to the new
代码 然后通过
URLSession code by mechanically
机械地为他们的旧的
making a URLSession for every
NSURLConnection 代码
old NSURLConnection they used to
加一个 URLSession 来把它们
have.
转化成 URLSession 代码
This is very inefficient and
这是一种非常没效率和
wasteful.
浪费的做法
For almost all of your apps what
对于大部分 app 来说
you want to have is just one
你们所需要的只是
URLSession, which can then have
一个 URLSession 它可以让你
as many tasks as you want.
完成你想要的任务
The only time you would want
你可能需要多于一个
more than one URLSession is when
URLSession 的唯一情况就是
you have groups of different
你有不同的操作组
operations that have radically
而且它们的要求都
different requirements.
截然不同
And in that case you might
这种情况下
create two different
你可能需要创建两个不同的
configuration objects and create
配置对象 并且
two different URLSessions using
用这两个配置对象创建
those two configuration objects.
两个不同的 URLSession
One example is private browsing
一个例子是 Safari 中的私密浏览模式
in Safari where each private
其中每个私密浏览
browsing window is its own
窗口都是
separate URLSession so that it
分别的 URLSession
doesn't share cookies and other
所以它们不会与其它会话分享
states with the other sessions.
Cookie 或者其它状态
Most apps can just have one
大多数的 app 都只能有一个
statically-allocated URLSession,
静态分配的 URLSession
and that's fine.
没关系
But if you do allocate
但是 如果你动态的
URLSessions dynamically,
分配 URLSession
remember to clean up afterwards.
就要记得事后清理
Either finish tasks and
要么完成任务然后
invalidate or invalidate and
使它失效 要么就废止
cancel.
然后取消它
But if you don't clean up,
但是如果你没有清理
you'll leak memory.
就会造成内存泄漏
We get developers asking us
有些开发者问我们
about convenience methods and
关于便捷方法和
delegate callbacks.
委托回调的问题
Delegate callbacks give you
委托回调会给予你
detailed step-by-step progress
详细的关于你的任务状态的
information on the state of your
逐步进展信息
The convenience methods, like
便捷方法 正如
the name suggests, are a quick
它的名字那样 是一种
and easy way of using the API.
快速简便的使用 API 的方法
With convenience methods you
使用便捷方法的话
don't get all the intermediate
你不会收到任何中间的
delegate callbacks, you just get
委托回调 你只会得到
the final result reported to the
汇报给 completionHandler 的
completionHandler.
最终结果
Don't mix and match both on the
不要在同一个 URLSession 上
same URLSession, pick one style
混合使用这两种方法
and be consistent.
选择其中一个并且保持一致
If you're using the
如果你使用
completionHandler, you will not
completionHandler 你不会获得
get the delegate callbacks with
委托回调 但是有以下
two exceptions.
两种例外情况
If networking is not currently
如果网络现在不可用
available and the task is
以及任务正在
waiting for connectivity, you'll
等待连接
be notified of that in case you
你会收到通知
want to show some indication in
以便你在你的
your UI.
UI 上显示任何提示
The other delegate method you
另一个你会收到通知的
may get notified is the
委托功能是
didReceive
didReceive
AuthenticationChallenge.
AuthenticationChallenge
So here's a summary of the
那么总结一下
options available to you.
你可以用的几种选项
Doing URLSessionTasks in your
我们推荐你
process with waits for
用 waitsForConnectivity 在进程中
connectivity as we recommend,
完成 URLSessionTasks
the task will start immediately
如果可以的话任务会立刻开始
if it can; or if it can't, it
但是如果无法立刻开始的话
will start at the first possible
它会在能开始的时候马上开始
You also have the option of
你还可以选择
doing tasks in the background.
在后台完成任务
And you can do background
你可以选择后台的
discretionary tasks, which will
自主任务
wait until the best time in
它会等到电池电量
terms of battery power and Wi-Fi
和 Wi-Fi 都最佳的时机开始
Now I have a couple of ongoing
现在我想要谈一谈一些
developments to talk about.
正在进行的开发
I'm sure many people in this
我想在座的很多人
room have heard about TLS 1.3.
都听说过 TLS 1.3
TLS, Transport Layer Security is
TLS 即安全传输层协议
the protocol that encrypts your
在网络上加密
data on the network to prevent
你的数据以防止
eavesdroppers from seeing it and
窃听者看到它
perhaps as importantly to make
也许同样重要的是
sure that you have connected to
保证你连到了
the server you intended to
你想要连接的
connect to.
那个服务器
TLS 1.2 is very old at this
在这个阶段 TLS 1.2
stage.
是很落伍了
It has a number of problems that
我们发现它有
have been discovered.
一系列的问题
And TLS 1.3 is almost finished.
TLS 1.3 已经基本完成了
That standard is not quite
标准还没有最终敲定
Apple is participating in that
目前苹果正在参与
IETF working group, and we
IETF 工作小组
expect that to be finished by
我们预计大概今年年底
the end of this year.
会完成
In the meantime, we do have a
同时 如果你们现在就想
draft implementation if you want
实验一下的话 我们有一个
to experiment with it right now.
执行草案
And if you check out the
如果你查看
security session from this Apple
本次苹果开发者大会的
Developer Conference, you can
安全部分
learn how to experiment with
你会了解到如何试用它
that.
你们可能还听说过
of is QUIC.
QUIC
QUIC is a new transport protocol
QUIC 是一个新的传输协议
designed to experiment with new
为试验那些
ideas that are hard to do with
TCP 无法支持的新点子而设计
TCP.
QUIC 最初是
experiment by some Google
一些谷歌工程师的一个试验
engineers, and it was a very
而这个试验
successful experiment.
非常成功
They learned a lot.
他们从中学到了很多
Some ideas were good, some
一些点子很好 同时也发现
turned out not to work as well
一些点子并不是像
as they hoped.
他们以为的那样
Those engineers have taken those
那些工程师把
lessons they learned to the
他们从中得到的经验带到了
IETF.
IETF
We have formed a new working
我们已经组成了一个
group to develop the IETF
新的工作小组来开发 IETF
standard QUIC protocol.
标准的 QUIC 协议
Apple is also participating in
苹果也参与了
that working group.
这个工作小组
That is not nearly as far long
它没有像
as TLS is, but that is also
TLS 那么成熟 但是它也已经
making good progress.
获得了很好的进展
Before we finish, one other
在结束之前
thing we should talk about,
我们还要再谈一件事情
Bonjour.
Bonjour
Fifteen year ago at this very
十五年前 也是在这个
convention center in San Jose,
圣荷西的会议中心
Steve Jobs announced Bonjour to
乔布斯向世界宣布了 Bonjour
And I got the opportunity to
而我有机会向你们
tell you all how it worked.
介绍它是如何工作的
A lot has happened since then.
那之后发生了很多事情
Since we launched it in 2004, we
自从我们在 2004 年推出了 Bonjour
brought out Bonjour for Windows,
我们将它用在了 Windows 上
for Linux.
用在了 Linux 上
We had Java APIs.
我们也有了 Java API
The next year Mac OS X 10.4
第二年 Mac OS X 10.4
introduced wide-area Bonjour to
推出了广域 Bonjour
complement the local
来补充在 Mac OS 10.2 中发布的
multicast-based Bonjour that was
本地的基于多路传送的
in the original Mac OS 10.2
Bonjour
The same year the Linux
同一年 Linux 开发者
community came out with a
做出了一个
completely independent
完全独立的
GPL-licensed implementation of
有 GPL 执照的
Bonjour called Avahi.
Bonjour 版本 叫做 Avahi
A couple of years after that,
之后几年
Apple shipped Back to My Mac,
苹果提出了 Back to My Mac
which is built on the wide-area
它是建立在 10.4 系统中推出的
Bonjour capabilities introduced
广域 Bonjour 功能上的
And in 2009 we brought out the
2009 年 我们推出了
Bonjour Sleep Proxy, which let
Bonjour Sleep Proxy
you get Back to Your Mac at
允许你在你的主页使用 Back to Your Mac
Home, even when it was asleep to
即使它为了节省电量
save power.
而处于休眠状态
In the years since then, Android
在那之后过了几年
adopted with Bonjour with their
2012 年安卓利用他们自己的 API
own native APIs in 2012.
也采用了 Bonjour
That was in API Level 16 for
如果你们中有人关注了的话
those of you paying attention.
那是在 API 16 级
And a couple of years ago,
几年前
Windows 10 added their own
Windows 10 添加了
native Bonjour support.
他们自己的 Bonjour 支持
Now, I know a lot of people in
现在 我知道在座的各位
this room are well aware of the
已经非常清楚这段历史了
We know about the major OS
我们知道采用 Bonjour 的
vendors adopting Bonjour.
主要操作系统供应商
But something else happened that
但是发生了一些其他的事情
surprised even me: Bonjour
甚至也让我感到惊讶
started showing up in a lot of
Bonjour 开始出现在很多
other places.
其他的地方
And I want to illustrate this
我想用我的一个
with just a little personal
个人经历来说明
I recently bought a new house.
我最近新买了一个房子
And as part of the process of
作为买新房的过程的
buying a new house, you often
一部分 你往往
end up buying a bunch of new
最终会买一些别的新东西
And I started adding things to
于是我开始往我的新家里
my home and connecting things to
添新东西 并且开始
the network.
把它们联入网络
And I started finding a bunch of
然后我开始发现
stuff showing up in Bonjour.
很多东西都采用了 Bonjour
Now, I bought a new printer; it
现在 我买了一个新打印机
had Bonjour.
它有 Bonjour
I bought some Access Network
我买了一些联网的
security cameras, they had
安全摄像头 它们也有 Bonjour
Bonjour.
这没有惊吓到我
we know printers and network
因为我们知道打印机和
cameras were among the first
联网摄像机是
devices to adopt Bonjour.
最先采用 Bonjour 的设备
But then I got a surround sound
然后我买了一个环绕声音响
amplifier and it had Wi-Fi, and
它有 Wi-Fi 功能
it had an embedded web server
并且它有一个采用 Bonjour 的
with Bonjour.
嵌入式网络服务器
Now, you can set up the
现在你可以使用
amplifier with the TV and the
电视和远程控制
remote control, but naming the
来设置这个音响
inputs with up, down, left,
但是输入名字时
right on the remote control one
使用远程控制器的上下左右四个键
character at a time is really
一个字母一个字母的输入
tedious.
是非常烦的
Being able to do this on my
能够在我的笔记本电脑
laptop or on my 27-inch iMac
或者 27 英寸屏幕的 iMac 上
with a keyboard and a mouse is
使用键盘和鼠标
such a nicer way to set up a new
来设置这个新设备
piece of equipment.
是多好的一件事儿
I bought another amplifier from
我从另一个不同的公司
different company, it also had
购买了另一个音响
Bonjour.
它也同样有 Bonjour
I got solar panels on the roof
我买了放在屋顶的
of the house to save on the
太阳能板来减轻
electricity bill, the inverter
电费的压力
has Wi-Fi with an embedded web
它的变频器有 Wi-Fi 功能
server advertised with Bonjour.
并有一个打着 Bonjour 广告的嵌入式网络服务器
So now with one click, I can see
现在我只需要点一下鼠标
a graph of how much power I've
就能看到一个
produced in the day.
今天产生了多少电量的图表
My most recent purchase was an
我最近买的一样东西是
irrigation controller to control
一个用来控制灌溉我的草坪的
the sprinklers that water my
灌溉控制器
It has Wi-Fi with an embedded
它也有 Wi-Fi 功能并且
web server advertised with
有一个打了 Bounjour 广告的
Bonjour.
嵌入式网络服务器
Compared to trying to program
比起试图
your garden sprinkles with a
用一个两位的 LCD 屏幕
two-digital LCD display and the
以及一个加减号的键
plus minus buttons, this is such
来设置你的喷头
a glorious experience to see it
能够同时在我的
all on my big iMac screen at the
iMac 的大屏幕上看到这一切
same time.
是多么美好的体验
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
So thank you to all you device
谢谢你们这些创造者
makers who are making these
创造了这么多
wonderful products.
美好的产品
For the app developers in the
对于在座的各位 app 开发者
room, how does this affect you?
这会对你有什么影响呢
The IETF DNS Service Discovery
IETF DNS Service Discovery
Working Group continues to make
工作小组继续取得进展
We have new enhancements to do
我们有了一些新改进
serve discovery on enterprise
可以在多路径传送不高效的
networks where multicast is not
企业网络上
efficient and on new mesh
以及新的网格状
network technologies that like
网络技术 比如
Thread that don't support
Thread 这样不支持多路径传送的网络
multicast well.
服务发现
The good news for app developers
对于 app 开发者而言
is this is all completely
好消息是它已经
transparent to your apps.
对你的 app 完全公开了
The APIs haven't changed because
API 没有什么变化
we anticipated these things even
因为我们甚至在 15 年前
15 years ago.
就预见到了这个问题
The only thing to remember is
唯一需要记住的是
when you do a browse call and
当你调用浏览器时
you get back a name, type, and
你会获得一个名称 类型
domain, pay attention to all
和域名 你要注意全部三个
You may be used to see the
你可能习惯于看到
domain always being local, but
域名总是本地的
now it may not be local.
然而现在它可能不是本地的
So when you call resolve, make
所以当你调用结束后
sure to pass the name, type, and
要记得回传你从
domain you got from the browse
浏览调用中获得的
call.
名称 类型和域名
And for the device makers out
而对于在座的设备制者来说
there, don't forget to support
不要忘记支持
link-local addressing.
本地链接寻址
Link-local addressing is the
本地链接寻址是
most reliable way to get to a
在本地网络中连接到一个设备的
device on the local network
最值得信赖的方式
because if you can't configure
因为如果你无法配置它
it, you can't misconfigure it.
你也就不会配置错了
[ Laughter ]
[ 笑声 ]
So to wrap up, in part one we
好了我们总结一下
talked about ongoing progress in
第一部分我们聊到了目前的
ECN.
ECN 方面的进展
It's now supported in clients
现在客户端和
and servers, the stage is set.
服务器都支持它 舞台已经搭好
Any ISP can now see an immediate
现在任何 ISP 都可以
benefit for their customers by
通过在关键的瓶颈链接处
turning on ECN at the key
打开 ECN 让他们的用户立刻感受到
bottleneck links.
它的好处
Continue testing your apps on
继续在 NAT64 上
NAT64.
测试你的 app
Mostly known use there, we're
在大部分已知的用户中
very happy everything is going
我们很高兴看到一切都顺利进行
We have a move to user space
我们在用户空间网络
networking, which also doesn't
方面也做了一些进步
change the APIs.
但是那也没有改变 API
But you may notice when you're
但是当你在
debugging and looking at stack
调试和查看堆栈跟踪时
traces, you may see symbols in
你可能会在堆栈跟踪中
the stack trace you're not used
看到一些你不熟悉的符号
to.
你可能看到
usage.
在 CPU 用量方面的不同
We wanted to you to be aware of
我们希望你可以了解这件事
that so it didn't surprise you.
这样你就不会过于惊讶
We have new capabilities in the
我们在网络扩展框架方面
network extension framework.
也提出了新的功能
And the big news, we have
一个重磅消息是
multipath TCP as used by Siri
用在 Siri 上的多路径 TCP
now available for your apps to
现在也可以用在
use as well.
你们的 app 上面了
Thank you.
谢谢
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
In part two, we covered some
在第二部分我们谈到了一些
enhancements in URLSession,
URLSession 的改进
especially the
尤其是
waitsForConnectivity, which is
waitsForConnectivity
really networking APIs done the
它是
way they always should have
真正的网络 API
done.
应该有的样子
When you ask us to do something,
当你要求我们做什么时
we should just do it, not bother
我们应该马上去做
you with silly error messages
而不是用一些现在无法完成的
that it can't be done right now.
出错信息来烦你
You ask us, we will do it when
你叫我们做 我们就在能做的时候
we can.
马上完成
I gave some tips about best
我还给出了一些最佳做法的
practices and news about ongoing
建议和一些正在进行的
developments.
开发的最新消息
You can get more information
你可以在网上找到
about this session on the web.
关于这场会议的更多信息
We have some other sessions we
我们推荐你们去听
recommend you hear that you'll
一些其它的会议
probably find interesting.
你或许会觉得它们也很有趣
Thank you.
谢谢